

Didarul Alam Rahat Frontend Developer

326, Ahmed Nagar, Mirpur-1, Dhaka +8801765849345 darahat42@gmail.com https://github.com/Darahat https://www.linkedin.com/in/didarul-alam-rahat-329b79bb/ https://twitter.com/darahat42

Personal Summary

A self motivated front end web developer who loves to work with creative frontend design and technologies with strong background of javaScript environment. Have been working for more than 1 years. A passionate ,self learner and mostly hard worker. Aim to work in a challenging work environment where can utilize expertise in technical skills, towards the development and implementation of the new ideas, contributing to growth of the organization.

Work Experience

Future Tech IT.

Mohammadpur, Dhaka.

URL:http://futuretechit.com/

Duration: February 2018 - Present

Role: Full Stack Developer

Responsibilities:The company provide Native Mobile App using nativescript/vue-cli.During working period we were work on a Android wallpaper app. Using nativescript we build a kids Rhymes app and Currency Converter app.

Technologies: Vue.js, Vuex, Vuex-Router, React Native, Vuetify, Bootstrap, Quaser, Nativescript, Express.js, MySQL.

NetDoc InfoTech Ltd Bangladesh.Baridhara, Dhaka.

URL:http://www.nditbd.com/

Duration: November 2017 - January 2018

Role: UI Developer Intern

Responsibilities:The company provide Software as a service for its clients. I was create and customize all phases of application design.

Technologies: HTML, CSS, ExtendJs, Twitter Bootstrap, REST API, JSON.

Freelance Web Developer

Duration: January 2015-December 2016.

Skills

Engineering

Problem solving, Reusable code writing, Cross browser compatibility, Responsive web design.

Languages

JavaScript, Java.

Frameworks/Technologies

Vue.Js, Vuex, Vuetify, Quaser, React Native, Redux, NativeScript, Bootstrap, Firebase, JSON, Express.js, MySQL, Sequelize, Extend JS.

Development Environment

OS-GNU/Linux, Windows.

Text Editors-Sublime Text.VSCode

Version Control-Git.

Projects

Nstack

Technologies: Vuejs, Vuex, Vue-router, Vuetify, meterial. js. animation.css, Express. js, Sequelize database.

Description:An attractive and clean designed blogging site build with

vuejs.posting,searching,commenting on blog post are main features of the blog.I learned here an attractive thing that is i used here 2 server one for front end and one for backend control.If unfortunately backend database stuck with error front end will run without any harm.

Git Link: https://github.com/Darahat/nstack.git

Live Link: http://nstack.surge.sh/#/index

Convert Currency

Technologies: Vuejs, Nativescript-vue, nativescript/vue-cli, Nativescript theme

Description: My Second nativescript android mobile app.lt can convert 249 countries currency. Here I use data. fixer. io to get real time currency rate of every country. It has very attractive and straight forward UI design so that any one can easily get understand what he should do.

Git Link: https://github.com/Darahat/Money-Converter.git

<u>Nubar</u>

Technologies: HTML5,CSS3,JavaScript,Bootstrap,Firebase.

Description: Real Time Micro blogging app . Using Firebase (NoSQL database) and core javascript.

Live Link: https://darahat.github.io/Nubar/

Git Link: https://github.com/Darahat/Nubar/tree/master

Mini Table Tennis Game

Technologies: HTML5(Canvas), CSS3, JavaScript,.

Description: Mini Table tennis game with some excellent physics rules using html5 canvas.

Live Link: https://darahat.github.io/Javascript-mini-game/
Git Link: https://github.com/Darahat/Javascript-mini-game.

Small Business Automation application (Desktop).

Technologies: Java SE.

Description: A Desktop small business analysis application which will help any type of grossary shop

calculation and business analysis regarding day ,month and yearly basis.

Git Link: https://github.com/Darahat/smallBussinessDesktopApplication.git.

Education

Bachelor of Science in Software Engineering(2013-2017)

Daffodil International University

Higher Secondary School Certificate (2010-2012)

Shaheed Sayeed Nazrul Islam College, Mymensingh

Secondary School Certificate (2010)

Mymensingh Zilla School